Guide to the William Goldman papers
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series IV: Manuscripts
  - Subseries 4.15: Research
    - GRAND HOTEL
      - Oversize newspapers and MGM Grand menues (Box 529, Folder 9)
    - GHOST AND THE DARKNESS
      - Various cuts and research reels of Ghost and the Darkness (Box 219)
      - Mission Impossible 2 1997; The Chamber 1996; Maverick 1994; Absolute Power 1997 (Box 221)
      - Maverick; National Pastime; Unholy City; Hype and Glory; Singing Out Loud (Box 220)
- Series V: Screenplays By Others
  - Maurice Richlin and Blake Edwards Soldier in the Rain, ( Carbon t.ms.) (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Maurice Richlin and Blake Edwards Soldier in the Rain, May 14, 1963, ( Notes and screenplay (third revised) (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Butch Cassidy and the Sundance Kid. Ephemera: magazine and newpaper clippings, brass belt buckle; award materials from the MPAA (Oscar) and others. (Box 12, Folder 2 - 6)
  - First draft of The Candidate by Jeremy Lerner (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Second draft of screenplay Brothers by Barry Kemp (Box 139, Folder 6 & 7)
  - Brothers screenplay by Barry Kemp (Box 140, Folder 1 & 2)
  - Memoirs of an Invisible Man screenplay 1992, 1987, ( Drafts including late drafts written by Robert Collector and Dana Olsen) (Box 159, Folder 1 - 6)
  - Dan and Tony Gilroy's draft of King Bill (Box 160, Folder 5 - 7)
  - Dolores Claiborne by Tony Gilroy (Box 200, Folder 5 & 6)
  - Dolores Claiborne by Tony Gilroy (Box 201, Folder 1 & 2)
- Series VI: Notes Clippings and Ephemera
  - Clippings, unidentified photos, Obelrin Ephemera up to 1973 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Notes and ephemera re. Family Affair, [ca. 1963] (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Fragment; Boys and Girls Together ephemera (Box 9, Folder 1 & 2)
  - Publicity broadside for Boys and Girls Together (Box 14/16/03)
  - Publicity for Boys and Girls Together, plus a review sent to Goldman (Box 225)
  - Drafts, notes and ephemera re. Butch Cassidy and the Sundance Kid (Box 10, Folder 4 - 7)
  - Ephemera: magazine and newpaper clippings, brass belt buckle; award materials from the MPAA (Oscar) and others. (Box 12, Folder 2 - 6)
  - Clippings from the European press for The Hot Rock and studio breakdowns of the script (Box 38, Folder 5)
  - Tony Bill lawsuit papers re. The Great Waldo Pepper (Box 42, Folder 7)
  - Materials pertaining to The Great Waldo Pepper and the Tony Bill lawsuit (Box 43, Folder 1 - 7)
  - Publicity brochure for The Great Waldo Pepper (Box 528, Folder 1)
  - Publication materials, contest materials, requests for the "reunion scene" re. Princess Bride (Box 48, Folder 2 - 7)
  - Drafts of the screenplay for Princess Bride; Fan mail; Reviews and publisher's material for the novel (Box 51, Folder 1 - 7)
  - Revised drafts of the screenplay for Princess Bride; Notes on the script; Copy of American Film 4 December 1983 containing a Princess Bride reference (Box 52, Folder 1 - 7)
  - Photostats of notices; Reviews; Magazines pertaining to the film (Box 56, Folder 7)
  - Drafts of the screenplay The Stepford Wives and MPAA voting materials for the Academy Awards 1973 and wine related research for the screenplay Year of the Comet (Box 60, Folder 1 - 5)
  - Academy Award voting materials, 1973 (Box 61, Folder 1 & 2)
  - Publicity materials for Year of the Comet (Box 66, Folder 3)
  - Reviews and notes for Marathon Man (Box 68, Folder 3 & 4)
  - Advertising and promotion for Marathon Man (Box 68, Folder 5)
  - Clippings, ads, book tie-in re. Marathon Man (Box 71, Folder 1)
  - Screenplay, reference material and reviews of the TV miniseries Mr. Horn (Box 75, Folder 1 - 3)
  - Reviews, publicity for All The Presidents Men (Box 84, Folder 3)
  - Cast of characters and publicity brochure for All The Predident's Men (Box 225)
  - Notes, clippings, press material re. A Bridge Too Far (Box 88, Folder 2 & 3)
  - Production records, call sheets, press books and clippings re. A Bridge Too Far (Box 88, Folder 6 & 7)
  - Clippings, publicity and a lawsuit for A Bridge Too Far (Box 89, Folder 1)
  - Publicity and reviews of Magic (Box 92, Folder 4)
  - Publicity, reviews and ideas for sequel to Magic (Box 92, Folder 8)
  - Promotional material and reviews of Heat (Box 96, Folder 3)
  - Production records for Heat (Box 98, Folder 3 - 4)
  - Stills and publicity from the production of the film Butch Cassidy and the Sundance Kid, the Early Years (Box 100, Folder 7)
  - Post production materials for Butch Cassidy and the Sundance Kid, the Early Years magazines, promotional materials, publicity, reviews (Box 101, Folder 1 & 2)
  - Publicity and promotion for Tinsel (Box 110, Folder 1)
  - Clippings and ads for Tinsel (Box 110, Folder 2)
  - Focus awards brochure (Box 127, Folder 2)
  - Color of Light publicity, book jackets, reviews and clippings (Box 130, Folder 4 - 7)
  - Draft of Adventures in the Screen Trade and Esquire excerpt from the same (Box 131, Folder 6)
  - Writer's Guild Information (Box 133, Folder 1)
  - Publicity, reviews, book jacket Adventures in the Screen Trade (Box 136, Folder 2)
  - Publicity, reviews and related material for Brothers (Box 139, Folder 1-3)
  - The Silent Gondoliers publication materials (Box 140, Folder 6)
  - Story ideas (Box 141, Folder 1)
  - Press kits and stills of the production for The Ghost and the Darkness (Box 151, Folder 6 & 7)
  - Draft of King Bill and Rhode Island film commission materials, 1986 (Box 160, Folder 1)
  - Singing Out Loud notes and clippings (Box 161, Folder 3)
  - Singing Out Loud notes and research (Box 161, Folder 4)
  - Singing Out Loud unproduced screenplay 1987 and ephemera form Cannes 1988 (Box 165, Folder 1-6)
  - 1988 Cannes Film Festival ephemera re. Hype and Glory (Box 166, Folder 1 - 6)
  - Hype and Glory reviews and articles (Box 172, Folder 1 & 2)
  - Special Olympics sponsorship brochure by Twins (Box 174, Folder 1)
  - Reviews and promotional materials re. Misery (Box 178, Folder 6)
  - Photos of an arranged screenwriters trip to the USSR (Box 189, Folder 3 & 4)
  - Absolute Power screenplay, Cannes 1996 Ephemera and Mission Impossible 2 research (Box 209, Folder 1-2)
- Series VII: Photographs
  - Clippings, unidentified photos, Obelrin Ephemera up to 1973 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Photos of an arranged screenwriters trip to the USSR (Box 189, Folder 3 & 4)
  - Manilow, Barry To: William Goldman, [Beverly Hills], 8 May 1984, (1p. a.l.s, with related photos and envelope) (Box 213)
  - Redford, Robert To: William Goldman, New York, Wengen Switzerland and Geneva Switzerland, n.d., and April 1970 - Nov. 1979, (1p. a.l.s., (with envelope and notes in Goldman's hand); a.l.s, with photo); telegram) (Box 213)
  - 1 B/W photo of [Frank Talman] standing beside a vintage airplane (Box 528, Folder 4)
  - The Color of Light (novel 1984) 11 x 14 of water; A Bridge Too Far 11 x 14 of producer James Levine (Box 528, Folder 6)
- Series VIII: Audio Visual
  - Sondheim, Stephen Tape of the song "No Mary Ann" for The Thing Of It Is (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Materials relating to an audio version of The Princess Bride (Box 56, Folder 4)
  - Audio cassette of The Princess Bride (Box 56, Folder 5)
  - Unidentified audio tape; A Year and a Day screenplay by Michael Leeson aka "Survivors" (Box 117, Folder 1)
  - A Chorus Line audio cassette (Box 141, Folder 5)
  - Various cuts and research reels of Ghost and the Darkness (Box 219)
  - Mission Impossible 2 1997; The Chamber 1996; Maverick 1994; Absolute Power 1997 (Box 221)
    [Copies of movies with corresponding research.]
  - Mission Impossible 2 1997: Various episodes of the TV show and one beta casette labled "Iran Canada" (Box 222)
  - Video and audio cassetts with research materials:; Maverick; National Pastime; Unholy City; Hype and Glory; Singing Out Loud (Box 220)
- Series IX: Memorabilia
  - Harmonica; Wallets (2); Hip Flask; Baseball Yo Yo; Travel Face Mirror (Box 225)
- Series X: Printed
  - Butch Cassidy and the Sundance Kid:; Ephemera: magazine and newpaper clippings, brass belt buckle; award materials from the MPAA (Oscar) and others. (Box 12, Folder 2 - 6)
  - Notes on Ross MacDonlad article and interview (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - Revised draft of The Princess Bride for Ballentine Books (Box 56, Folder 3)
  - Photostats of notices, reviews; magazines pertaining to The Princess Bride (Box 56, Folder 7)
  - Research magazines re. The Stepford Wives (Box 57, Folder 4 - 7)
  - Magazines and clippings pertaining to the women's movement in the early 1970s as background material for The Stepford Wives (Box 58, Folder 1 - 5)
  - All The President's Men (1974-1975); Research material / magazines (Box 78, Folder 1 - 7)
  - Production records, call sheets, press books and clippings re. A Bridge Too Far (Box 88, Folder 6 & 7)
  - Post production materials for Butch Cassidy and the Sundance Kid, the Early Years magazines, promotional materials, publicity, reviews (Box 101, Folder 1 & 2)
  - The Right Stuff research notes; This New Ocean, A History of Project Mercury by Lloyd S. Swnson, Jr. James Grimwood and Charles Alexander; The Right Stuff by Tom Wolfe (Box 120, Folder 2)
  - Unpublished nonfiction research re. Wait Till Next Year (1987) (Box 153, Folder 1- 5)
  - Research including notes, clippings, draft pages, magazines copy newspapers re. Wait Till Next Year, 1987-1988 (Box 154, Folder 1 - 6)
  - Hype and Glory reviews and articles (Box 172, Folder 1 & 2)
  - Copies of magazine articles re. Unholy City (Box 181, Folder 5)
  - Articles for New York Magazine (Box 189, Folder 1 - 6)
  - New York Magazine Articles, 1991-1994 (Box 190, Folder 1 -5)
  - Articles about Goldman (Box 212, Folder 1)
  - A signet ring and a monogrammed flask Two Weeks in the Sun, a Cannes Notebook by Roger Ebert; Miss America Through the Looking Glass The Story Behind the Scenes by Nancie s. Martin; Hostage to Fortune Atlantic City and Casino Gambling by Michael Pollock; New Jersey History by Peter Kross; By The Beautiful Sea by Charles E. Funnel; Becoming a Beauty Queen, The Complete Guide by Barbara Peterson Burwell and Polly Peterson Bowles (Box 212, Folder 2)
  - Hamill, Pete To: William Goldman, Encino, CA, 3 Jan. 1974, (1p. t.l.s, with envelope) (Box 213)
    [6 marked books added from Hype and Glory Box 165]
  - Articles pertaining to military aircraft. Oversize magazines:; The Los Angels Herald Examiner 15 December 1969; Life 12 June 1970; Look 30 June 1970 (Box 528, Folder 1)
  - Mounted film article by Judith Christ: The Return of the Pre-Bond Man New York Herald Tribune 3 April 1966 (Box 528, Folder 3)
  - Oversize magazines pertaining to All the Presidents Men: The New York Times Magazine 22 July 1973 and 13 January 1974; The Boston Globe Magazine 25 August 1974 (Box 528, Folder 5)
  - Photocopies of Motion Picture Herald articles that rank motion picture stars in the sixties and seventies.; Rolling Stone 18 March 1982 (Box 528, Folder 7)
    [Research: Adventures in the Screen Trade]
  - Research materials Adventures in the Screen Trade; photocopies of articles from Motion Picture Herald regarding Burt Reynolds (Box 528, Folder 8)
  - Research for Brothers novel: oversize magazines.; New York Times Magazine 4 March 1984 (Box 528, Folder 9)
  - Research material for Unholy City: Official Detective Stories 25 May 1938 Bombing the Lid Off Los Angeles (Box 528, Folder 12)
  - Marathon Man, (2 posters, 1 periodical) (Box 318, Folder 1)
  - All The President's Men, New York, 1974, (2 newspapers) (Box 318, Folder 2)
  - Magic, (5 pages manuscript, 3 periodicals, 1 newspaper) (Box 318, Folder 3)
  - Butch and Sundance: The Early Years, (7 sheets posters) (Box 318, Folder 4)
  - Wait Until Next Year, Chicago, 1987, (4 newspapers, 1 towel) (Box 318, Folder 5)
  - Hype and Glory, Atlantic City, 1988, (2 periodicals, 10 clippings, 1 advert, 2 boards) (Box 318, Folder 6)
  - Wait Until Next Year, [v.p.], 1988, (3 periodicals, 1 clipping) (Box 318, Folder 7)
  - The National Pastime, [v.p.], 1989 & 1991, (8 newspapers, 4 sheets notes) (Box 318, Folder 8 & 9)
  - Absolute Power & Mission Impossible 2, [v.p.], 1996 & 1997, (11 clippings) (Box 318, Folder 10)
  - Terrorism project, [v.p.], 1997, (37 clippings) (Box 318, Folder 11)
  - Leather chair strap support with name stamped "William Goldman" (Box 318, Folder 12)
  - Books, annotated by Goldman, used as background research for his various projects., (15 books) (Box 226)
  - Books, annotated by Goldman or signed by others used as background research for his various projects., (20 books) (Box 227)
  - Books, annotated by Goldman or signed by others used as background research for his various projects., (23 books) (Box 228)
  - Books, annotated by Goldman or signed by others used as background research for his various projects., (18 books) (Box 229)